<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RUSE 2019</title>
    <link>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on RUSE 2019</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 17:44:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://rusesymposium.org.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical information</title>
      <link>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 17:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/info/</guid>
      <description>Registration and fees N.B. Problem resolved &amp;ndash; registration is back to normal. Due to a technical issue, the eStore link below says the conference is &amp;ldquo;fully booked&amp;rdquo;. This is not the case. If you wish to attend the conference, please do show up – we will sort the technical issue ASAP, at which point you will be able to pay the fee. Our apologies for the inconvenience.
Register here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programme</title>
      <link>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/programme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 17:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/programme/</guid>
      <description>Day 1: Tuesday 20 August 09:00&amp;ndash;10:00 Registration 10:00&amp;ndash;11:00 Keynote 1  Richard A. Blythe
Competition between linguistic variants at the individual and population scale (abstract)  11:00&amp;ndash;11:30 Coffee 11:30&amp;ndash;13:00 Session 1: Evolutionary Dynamics  James Burridge, Tam Blaxter &amp;amp; Bert Vaux
Testing the evolutionary paths of grammar (abstract) Andres Karjus, Richard A. Blythe, Simon Kirby &amp;amp; Kenny Smith
Changing communicative need predicts lexical competition and contributes to language change (abstract) Ilja Seržant</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keynotes</title>
      <link>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/keynotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 17:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/keynotes/</guid>
      <description>Ricardo Bermúdez-Otero, University of Manchester The initiation and incrementation of sound change: momentum vs social meaning In this talk I argue that language learners are community-oriented and momentum-driven: they are community-oriented in that they acquire and obey a mental representation of the linguistic norm of their speech community; they are momentum-driven in that their mental representation of the community norm includes an age vector encoding linguistic differences between age groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers</title>
      <link>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 17:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/cfp/</guid>
      <description>The call has ended: it is no longer possible to submit abstracts.
Different theories and models attribute linguistic variation and change to different causes. Currently, significant tension exists between approaches that explain variation and change in terms of a parametric approach to the structure of grammar and the language learner&amp;rsquo;s interaction with primary linguistic data, and approaches that instead derive variation and change from usage effects and the social embedding of language.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>