<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RUSE 2019</title>
    <link>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on RUSE 2019</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 17:44:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://rusesymposium.org.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical information</title>
      <link>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 17:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/info/</guid>
      <description>Venue The RUSE symposium will take place on the University of Manchester&amp;rsquo;s Sackville Street Campus in the heart of Manchester city centre, just a 5-minute walk from Piccadilly train station or a 10-minute walk from Oxford Road station.
 Registration and fees Register here.
Fees are as follows and include both days of the symposium, with a buffet lunch and refreshments throughout the day. We reserve a limited number of places for PhD students with a subsidized fee through a separate application procedure, details of which will be made available once registration opens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programme</title>
      <link>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/programme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 17:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/programme/</guid>
      <description>Day 1: Tuesday 20 August 09:00&amp;ndash;10:00 Registration 10:00&amp;ndash;11:00 Keynote 1  Richard A. Blythe
Competition between linguistic variants at the individual and population scale  11:00&amp;ndash;11:30 Coffee 11:30&amp;ndash;13:00 Session 1: Evolutionary Dynamics  James Burridge, Tam Blaxter &amp;amp; Bert Vaux
Testing the evolutionary paths of grammar Andres Karjus, Richard A. Blythe, Simon Kirby &amp;amp; Kenny Smith
Changing communicative need predicts lexical competition and contributes to language change Ilja Seržant</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keynotes</title>
      <link>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/keynotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 17:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/keynotes/</guid>
      <description>Ricardo Bermúdez-Otero, University of Manchester Title and abstract TBA
Richard A. Blythe, University of Edinburgh Competition between linguistic variants at the individual and population scale A number of documented language changes (e.g., names for an object, or alternative grammatical structures) can be couched as a competition between an existing ‘conventional’ variant and one or more incoming ‘innovations’. Mathematical models allow one to determine how processes acting at the individual speaker level (such as matching the frequencies of existing variants, cognitive biases that favour specific innovations or sociolinguistic prestige effects) manifest themselves at the population scale, with social network structures mediating between them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers</title>
      <link>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 17:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rusesymposium.org.uk/cfp/</guid>
      <description>The call has ended: it is no longer possible to submit abstracts.
Different theories and models attribute linguistic variation and change to different causes. Currently, significant tension exists between approaches that explain variation and change in terms of a parametric approach to the structure of grammar and the language learner&amp;rsquo;s interaction with primary linguistic data, and approaches that instead derive variation and change from usage effects and the social embedding of language.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>